Dathan Ellis

Boulder, CO

334 328 9101 dathanellis@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Software engineer with 14+ years of IT experience including design, development, testing, business analysis, and team management. I am an accomplished full stack developer with advanced skills in .NET, JavaScript and SQL, while focusing on performance and efficiency. In my tenure, I have built web and mobile applications on several platforms for industries such as government, aerospace, telecom, co-packing, retail, organic foods, and nonprofits.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Developer | DragonDev

Boulder, CO | 2013-2015

Developed and maintained multiple custom web and mobile applications for several clients on a wide variety of platforms.

- Created custom applications from the ground up to meet and exceed the needs and vision of every client
- Exercised Agile/Scrum methodology to fulfill aggressive deadlines and complex requirements
- Provided scoping for new projects and updates to determine MVP
- Generated new business and nurtured key relationships for current clients
- Managed and mentored developer team between diverse programs

Software Engineer | Civil Air Patrol

Maxwell AFB, AL | 2006-2013

Designed and developed web tools for the US Air Force Auxiliary in an environment with over 80 web applications and 60,000 users.

- Developed web apps for cadets, aerospace education, mailroom administration, public relations, inventory logistics, and management dashboards
- Trained personnel on and off site on web app functionality
- Conducted meetings among customers and technicians to gather requirements and deliverables
- Developed real time reports for users and management
- Nominated for Employee of the Quarter on multiple occasions

QA/Programmer | Integrated Computer Solutions, Inc. (ICS)

Maxwell-Gunter AFB - DISA, AL | 2003-2006

Implemented and tested security automation on servers (SRR) for all branches of the armed forces.

- Tested server toolkits built on Windows and UNIX platforms
- Managed bugs and features for each release
- Administered and maintained server development lab
- Produced SQL gueries and custom reports for management
- Trained personnel off-site, via classroom or one-on-one environments on scripts and web toolkit
- Prepared technical papers for compliance on team software documentation

Software Tester | LJT & Associates, Inc.

Maxwell AFB - Gunter Annex, AL | 2002-2003

Tested the Secretary of the Air Force (SAF/FMPT) financial web application using custom reports and automated test tools.

- Created use cases and automated scripts for functional, regression and load testing
- Performed automated load testing for the ABIDES funds management system
- Prepared technical papers and provided editorial assistance for team documentation
- Programmed updates to the department's custom problem reporting tool

Business Analyst | Colonial BancGroup

Montgomery, AL | 2001-2002

Coordinated project teams and managers in banking systems across multiple domains.

- Led technical meetings among programmers, system engineers, analysts and management
- Tested banking and other financial legacy and custom PC software applications
- Implemented test tools and created the bank's first automated test script library
- Managed multiple internal projects for software development across domains
- Planned and executed procedures based on gathered requirements and objectives

SKILLS

- VB.NET, C#, Java, Ruby on Rails, Javascript, jQuery, AngularJS, Titanium, SQL Server, MySQL, Firebase, JSON, SSRS, Crystal Reports, SAP Web Intelligence, and Android
- Exceptional communication skills with the ability to understand and interpret the operational needs of businesses at all levels
- Experienced team leader feeding an ability to manage cross-functional teams
- Extraordinary ability to create productive relationships with both new and current clients
- Excellent capacity to deliver meaningful information and ideas through written word
- Critical and creative thinker that examines all sides of an issue to escalate results

EDUCATION

Auburn University Montgomery

BS-BA Management Information Systems | 1996-2000

CLEARANCE

Top Secret Clearance - currently expired